PIOTR WITTCHEN | RESUME

email piotr@wittchen.io website wittchen.io github wittchen.io/gh personal projects wittchen.io/ps +48 512 514 831 wittchen.io/in stackoverflow wittchen.io/so selected talks phone linkedin wittchen.io/ts

I am the software developer with more than 7 years of experience in creating mobile and web applications in Java and more than 10 years of total programming experience. I am aware of the good software development practices, automated testing, design patterns, different programming paradigms and clean code principles. I continuously learn new things and improve my skills to deliver pragmatic, well-tested, high-quality solutions.

Professional experience

Enginiety, Software Engineer | May 2019 - now, Gliwice, Poland

Development and maintenance of the telco e-commerce web application. Tech Stack: Java, Spring, SAP Hybris Commerce, JUnit, AssertJ, Mockito, Ant, Git, Jenkins, Bash

SAP, Software Engineer | Dec 2015 - May 2019, Gliwice, Poland

Development and maintenance of the SAP Hybris Commerce Platform (Backoffice, PCM, PCH). **Tech Stack**: Java, Spring, ZK, SAP Hybris Commerce, Ant, Maven, Gradle, JUnit, FEST, AssertJ, Mockito, Git, Jenkins, Azure, Docker

Future Processing, Software Engineer | Sep 2012 - Dec 2015, Gliwice, Poland

Development and maintenance of Android mobile applications. Short-term work on web and desktop Java applications. Tech Stack: Java, Android, Dagger, Guice, Otto, Retrofit, RxJava, JUnit, Mockito, FEST, Robolectric, Spring Boot, REST-assured, JWebServices, Swing, CORBA, Ant, Gradle, SVN, TFS, Git, Jenkins

Future Processing, IT Security Engineer | Jun 2012 - Sep 2012, Gliwice, Poland

Black-box security testing of the web applications and preparing security reports. **Tools**: Burp, Fiddler, WireShark, Arachni, Chrome Dev Tools

Freelance, Web Developer | Feb 2006 - Jun 2012, Gliwice, Poland (working remotely)

Development and maintenance of the websites and web applications. Tech Stack: PHP, Kohana, Codelgniter, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

Yakamedia, Web Developer | Sep 2009 - Mar 2010, Gliwice, Poland

Development of the websites and e-commerce applications. Tech Stack: PHP, Sote Shop, MySQL, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery

3W Serwisy Informacyjne, Web Developer | Oct 2005 - Feb 2006, Gliwice, Poland

Development and maintenance of the websites for the UN Information Center in Warsaw.

Tech Stack: PHP, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Flash, CVS

Education

Silesian University of Technology in Gliwice, Poland, Master's Degree, 2014

Macrofaculty of Automatic Control, Electronics and Computer Science, full-time studies in English language, major: Computer Science Master Thesis: Brain-Computer Interface for Mobile Devices (Tech Stack: Java, Android, Guice, SQLite, Dropbox SDK, ThinkGear SDK)

Silesian University of Technology in Gliwice, Poland, Engineer's Degree, 2012

Macrofaculty of Automatic Control, Electronics and Computer Science, full-time studies in English language, major: Computer Science Engineering Project: Implementation of the Flight Finder Internet Booking Engine (Tech Stack: PHP, Kohana, MySQL, JS, Flight Finder API)

Languages

Polish - native, English - professional working proficiency

Sharing the knowledge and open-source contributions

- I gave 20+ talks during conferences and meetups in Poland and abroad: http://wittchen.io/talks
- I published 140+ articles on my technical blog: http://wittchen.io
- According to Coder Stats, my projects have 5000+ stars and 700+ forks on GitHub: http://wittchen.io/cs
- According to Git Awards, I am the top 5 open-source Java developer in Poland: http://wittchen.io/ga
- I have 2700+ points on StackOverflow so far: http://wittchen.io/so

Programming, Linux, sports (gym, football, swimming, bike, wakeboard), traveling, music, playing the guitar

I hereby give consent for my personal data included in my application to be processed for the purposes of the recruitment process under the Personal Data Protection Act as of 29 August 1997, consolidated text: Journal of Laws 2016, item 922 as amended.